there was this suspense that built because the actual tweets, you had no control over when you would read them. They were coming at a pretty regular clip, but as the story was building, normally, as a reader, you control how fast you move through a text, but in this case, The New Yorker did, and they were sending you bit by bit by bit, and you had this suspense of waiting for the next line. Another great example of fiction and the short story on Twitter, Elliott Holt is an author who wrote a story called "Evidence." It began with this tweet: "On November 28 at 10:13 p.m., a woman identified as Miranda Brown, 44, of Brooklyn, fell to her death from the roof of a Manhattan hotel." It begins in Elliott's voice, but then Elliott's voice recedes, and we hear the voices of Elsa, Margot and Simon, characters that Elliott created on Twitter specifically to tell this story, a story from multiple perspectives leading up to this moment at 10:13 p.m. when this woman falls to her death. These three characters brought an authentic vision from multiple perspectives. One reviewer called Elliott's story "Twitter fiction done right," because she did. She captured that voice and she had multiple characters and it happened in real time. Interestingly, though, it wasn't just Twitter as a distribution mechanism. It was also Twitter as a production mechanism. Elliott told me later she wrote the whole thing with her thumbs. She laid on the couch and just went back and forth between different characters tweeting out each line, line by line. I think that this kind of spontaneous creation of what was coming out of the characters' voices really lent an authenticity to the characters themselves, but also to this format that she had created of multiple perspectives in a single story on Twitter. As you begin to play with flexible identity online, it gets even more interesting as you start to interact with the real world. Things like Invisible Obama or the famous "binders full of women" that came up during the 2012 election cycle, or even the fan fiction universe of "West Wing" Twitter in which you have all of these accounts for every single one of the characters in "The West Wing," including the bird that taps at Josh Lyman's window in one single episode. (Laughter) All of these are rapid iterations on a theme. They are creative people experimenting with the bounds of what is possible in this medium. You look at something like "West Wing" Twitter, in which you have these fictional characters that engage with the real world. They comment on politics, they cry out against the evils of Congress. Keep in mind, they're all Democrats. And they engage with the real world. They respond to it. So once you take flexible identity, anonymity, engagement with the real world, and you move beyond simple homage or parody and you put these tools to work in telling a story, that's when things get really interesting. So during the Chicago mayoral election there was a parody account. It was Mayor Emanuel. It gave you everything you wanted from Rahm Emanuel, particularly in the expletive department. This foul-mouthed account followed the daily activities of the race, providing commentary as it went. It followed all of the natural tropes of a good, solid Twitter parody account, but then started to get weird. And as it progressed, it moved from this commentary to a multi-week, real-time science fiction epic in which your protagonist, Rahm Emanuel, engages in multi-dimensional travel on election day, which is -- it didn't actually happen. I double checked the newspapers. And then, very interestingly, it came to an end. This is something that doesn't usually happen with a Twitter parody account. It ended, a true narrative conclusion. And so the author, Dan Sinker, who was a journalist, who was completely anonymous this whole time, I think Dan -- it made a lot of sense for him to turn this into a book, because it was a narrative format in the end, and I think that turning it into a book is representative of this idea that he had created something new that needed to be translated into previous formats. One of my favorite examples of something that's happening on Twitter right now, actually, is the very absurdist Crimer Show. Crimer Show tells the story of a supercriminal and a hapless detective that face off in this exceptionally strange lingo, with all of the tropes of a television show. Crimer Show's creator has said that it is a parody of a popular type of show in the U.K., but, man, is it weird. And there are all these times where Crimer, the supercriminal, does all of these TV things. He's always taking off his sunglasses or turning to the camera, but these things just happen in text. I think borrowing all of these tropes from television and additionally presenting each Crimer Show as an episode, spelled E-P-P-A-S-O-D, "eppasod," presenting them as episodes really, it creates something new. There is a new "eppasod" of Crimer Show on Twitter pretty much every day, and they're archived that way. And I think this is an interesting experiment in format. Something totally new has been created here out of parodying something on television. I think in nonfiction real-time storytelling, there are a lot of really excellent examples as well. RealTimeWWII is an account that documents what was happening on this day 60 years ago in exceptional detail, as if you were reading the news reports from that day. And the author Teju Cole has done a lot of experimentation with putting a literary twist on events of the news. In this particular case, he's talking about drone strikes. I think that in both of these examples, you're beginning to see ways in which people are telling stories with nonfiction content that can be built into new types of fictional storytelling. So with real-time storytelling, blurring the lines between fact and fiction, the real world and the digital world, flexible identity, anonymity, these are all tools that we have accessible to us, and I think that they're just the building blocks. They are the bits that we use to create the structures, the frames, that then become our settlements on this wide open frontier for creative experimentation. Thank you. (Applause)
se creaba un suspenso porque a los tuits reales, uno no controlaba cuándo los leería. Venían a un ritmo bastante regular, pero a medida que se desarrolla la historia, normalmente, como lector, uno controla el ritmo de lectura, pero en este caso, lo hacía The New Yorker y hacían entregas poquito a poco, y uno sentía el suspenso de esperar la próxima línea. Otro gran ejemplo de ficción y de cuento en Twitter. Elliot Holt es la escritora que escribió el cuento "Evidence". Empieza con este tuit: "El 28 de noviembre a las 22:13 hs, una mujer identificada como Miranda Brown, 44 años, de Brooklyn, cae desde la azotea de un hotel de Manhattan y muere". Empieza con la voz de Elliott, pero luego su voz se aleja y escuchamos las voces de Elsa, Margot y Simon, personajes que Elliott creó en Twitter específicamente para contar esta historia, una historia con múltiples aristas que llevan a este momento de las 22:13 hs cuando esta mujer cae y muere. Estos tres personajes crean una visión auténtica de varios puntos de vista. Un crítico llamó al cuento de Elliott "Ficción en Twitter bien hecha", porque lo hizo. Capturó esa voz tuvo múltiples personajes y sucedió en tiempo real. Curiosamente, sin embargo, Twitter no era solo un mecanismo de distribución. También era un mecanismo de producción. Elliott me dijo después que escribió todo con sus pulgares. Recostada en el sofá iba y venía tecleando distintos caracteres tuiteando cada línea, línea por línea. Creo que esta especie de creación espontánea de lo que salía de las voces de los personajes realmente le confirió autenticidad a los personajes en sí, pero también a este formato que ella creó de múltiples aristas en un cuento de Twitter. Conforme uno empieza a jugar con la identidad flexible online se pone cada vez más interesante cuando uno empieza a interactuar con el mundo real. Cosas como Invisible Obama o el meme &quot;binders full of women&quot; que aparecieron en la campaña electoral del 2012 o incluso el universo de fans en Twitter de "West Wing" en el que están todas estas cuentas una para cada personaje de "The West Wing", estaba hasta el pájaro que en un episodio golpea la ventana de Josh Lyman. (Risas) Son todas iteraciones rápidas sobre un tema. Son gente creativa que experimenta con los límites de lo posible en este medio. Vemos cosas como "West Wing" Twitter, en la que personajes de ficción interactúan con el mundo real. Hablan de política, despotrican contra el Congreso. Recuerden son todos demócratas. E interactúan con el mundo real. Le responden. Entonces, si tomamos la identidad flexible, el anonimato, la interacción con el mundo real, y sobrepasamos el simple homenaje o la parodia y ponemos todo eso al servicio de narrar una historia, ahí la cosa se pone muy interesante. Durante la elección de la alcaldía de Chicago había una cuenta de parodia. Era Mayor Emanuel. Te daba todo lo que querías de Rahm Emanuel, sobre todo las blasfemias. Esta cuenta malhablada seguía las actividades diarias de la campaña y comentaba lo ocurrido. Seguía la retórica normal de una cuenta de parodia buena y sólida, pero luego empezó a volverse extraña. Conforme avanzaba, pasó de ese comentario a una épica de ciencia ficción en tiempo real de varias semanas en la que el protagonista, Rahm Emanuel, emprende un viaje multidimensional el día de la elección que... nunca ocurrió. Verifiqué en los periódicos. Y luego, muy interesante, llegó a su fin. Esto es algo que no sucede por lo general con una cuenta de parodia en Twitter. Termina con una verdadera conclusión narrativa. El escritor Dan Sinker, periodista, era completamente anónimo todo este tiempo. Creo que para Dan era importante convertir esto en un libro, porque al final era un formato narrativo, y creo que convertirlo en libro es un signo de que creó algo nuevo que había que traducir a los formatos previos. Uno de mis ejemplos favoritos de algo que está ocurriendo ahora en Twitter, es el muy absurdo Crimer Show. Crimer Show cuenta la historia de un súpercriminal y un detective desventurado que se enfrentan con un lenguaje muy extraño, con los lugares comunes de la tele. El creador de Crimer Show dijo que es una parodia de un tipo popular de espectáculo del Reino Unido, pero, hombre, es extraño. Crimer, el súpercriminal, hace todo lo típico de la TV: siempre se quita las gafas de sol o gira hacia la cámara, pero todo esto sucede en el texto. Creo que tomar todos estos lugares comunes de la tele y además presentar cada Crimer Show como un episodio, deletreado E-P-P-A-S-O-D [parodia promo de tv] presentándolos como episodios realmente crea algo nuevo. Hay un nuevo "epasodio" de Crimer Show en Twitter casi a diario, y se archivan así. Creo que esto es un experimento interesante con el formato. Algo totalmente nuevo creado a partir de la parodia de algo de la tele. Creo que en la narrativa de no ficción en tiempo real también hay muchos ejemplos excelentes. RealTimeWWII es una cuenta que documenta lo ocurrido hoy pero hace 60 años con un detalle excepcional como si uno leyera las noticias de ese día. Y el escritor Teju Cole experimentó mucho con eso de darle un giro literario a las noticias. En este caso particular, está hablando de ataques con drones. Creo que en ambos ejemplos empezamos a ver formas de narrativa con contenido de no ficción que pueden constituir nuevos tipos de narrativa de ficción. Así, la narrativa en tiempo real difumina la línea entre realidad y ficción, el mundo real y el mundo digital, la identidad flexible, el anonimato, son herramientas que tenemos a mano, y creo que son solo bloques de construcción. Son elementos que usamos para crear estructuras, marcos, sobre las cuales apoyar la exploración de esta frontera abierta a la experimentación. Gracias. (Aplausos)